<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[compendium]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>compendium</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 12:45:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 12:45:06 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Alchemist<br><br>Alchemists power both in and out of combat comes largely from their mastery of potions, tonics, bombs and 'perfumes'.<br><br><a data-href="Attributes &amp; Skills#Base Attributes" href="core-gameplay/attributes-&amp;-skills.html#Base_Attributes" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Attributes &amp; Skills &gt; Base Attributes</a><br><br>
<br>Charisma
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>Light Armour
<br><br>
<br>Simple Weapons
<br>Slings
<br>Throwables
<br><br>Alchemist's Rod<br><br>
<br>Operator
<br><br><br>Alchemists empower their brews with a variety of catalysts that modify and enhance the base effects. Catalyst cards can be added to their Combat Deck and be used to modify the effects of consumables.<br><br>Alchemists experience handling dangerous materials allows them to safely carry more Consumables, increasing base capacity to 7.<br><br>Alchemists start with level 3 Alchemy and can choose 2 Alchemical Mixtures to master. Mastered mixtures require half the reagents to create and have a Chance to yield additional Consumables when brewed. This also unlocks the consumables Mastery effect.]]></description><link>classes/alchemist/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Alchemist/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:58:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Starting Deck]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Starting Deck:<br>
<br>Accelerating Catalyst (x4) - Increases the potency of your Alchemical Mixtures, add your spell power to the next Bomb, or Offensive Tonic you use.
<br>Voluminous Catalyst (x3) - Gives your next Bomb or Offensive tonic the Area of Effect trait, with a Radius of 10ft. Add half your spell power to the damage.
<br>Basic Attack (x5) - Make a basic attack, dealing Weapon Damage + Attack Power.
<br>Stalwart Catalyst (x2) - Double the Defence bonus from your next Defensive Tonic.
<br>Numbing Brew (x3) - Reaction: Increase Defence Rating by 
]]></description><link>classes/alchemist/starting-deck.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Alchemist/Starting Deck.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 16:00:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Bard<br><br>Bards are smooth talking muses who have studied the ancient of arts of Melody, which uses music to create order out of the energies of the universe. Bards can use these melodies to take away their ally's weariness, tear down enemies, and influence the minds of others.<br><br>Charisma<br><br>
<br>Faith
<br>Dexterity
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>Clothing
<br><br>
<br>Simple Weapons
<br><br>Instrument<br><br>
<br>Melody
<br><br><br>Known for their quick wit and powers of persuasion, Bards start as experts in Persuasion.<br><br>Bard's dress to slay, but also to survive. Bards can use stylish clothing to increase their Defence Rating.]]></description><link>classes/bard/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Bard/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:05:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Class Details - OLD]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Bards are smooth talking muses who have studied the ancient of arts of Melody, which uses music to create order out of the energies of the universe. Bards can use these melodies to take away their ally's weariness, tear down enemies, and influence the minds of others.<br>Primary Stat: Charisma<br>
Recommended Secondary Stats: Faith, Dexterity, Stamina<br>
Armour Specializations: Clothing (See Sharp Dresser)<br>
Weapon Specializations: Simple Weapons (AP)<br>
Damage Source: Instrument<br>
Primal Card Types: Melody<br><br>Silver Tongue: Known for their quick wit and powers of persuasion, Bards start as experts in Persuasion.<br>Sharp Dresser: Bard's dress to slay, but also to survive. Bards can use stylish clothing to increase their Defence Rating.<br>Master of their Art: Bard's have spent years mastering their musical skills, specializing in a specific genre. Select one of the following:<br>Classical:<br>
Classical melodies bring order to the chaos, bolstering the defence of of allies and using complex strategies to stay one step ahead of enemies. Gain the ability to select Classical Primal Cards on level up and the following features:<br>
Crescendo:  Your mastery of Classical melodies have allowed your melodies to peak in an inspiring Crescendo. Allies who participate in your Strategy cards heal for half your Spell Power when the conditions are met, and the Strategy card's effect is Heightened.<br>
Perfect Timing: Years of playing in tune with others has allowed you to tune into the rhythm of battle. You start each combat round with +2 Ability Points.<br>Modern:<br>
Modern melodies are unpredictable and can sound discordant to the untrained ear. This unpredictability and discordance can cause chaos among enemies and bolster your allies. Gain the ability to select Modern Primal Cards on level up and the following features:<br>
Between the Notes: Many say that the notes that aren't played as just as the important as the notes that you play. Add +1 Spell Power to the effect of your next Melody card for each non Melody card you played this combat round.<br>
Off Beat: Enemies struggle to follow the complex beat of your melodies and leave openings for attack. After being hit by an Offensive Melody, enemies have their Defence Rating reduced by 1 for one round.<br>Experimental:<br>
Experimental melodies are aggressive, loud and fast paced. These melodies bolster your and your allies attacks and deal huge damage. Gain the ability to select Experimental Primal Cards on level up and the following features:<br>
Stage Presence: You know how to command a presence on stage, and this shows on the battlefield. Enemies that are affected by your melodies focus their attention on you, for 1 round their Attack Power and Spell Power are reduced by half if they attack other targets.<br>
Heavy Metal: Years of performing in full costume and carrying heavy gear have conditioned your physique. You gain the ability to wear Medium and Heavy Armour.<br>
Mosh Mindset: Your countless hours spent amid the chaos of mosh pits has given you an uncanny focus in any environment. You can cast Spells with no negative effects while Threatened.]]></description><link>classes/bard/class-details-old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Bard/Class Details - OLD.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 17:17:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Classical]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Classical melodies bring order to the chaos, bolstering the defence of of allies and using complex strategies to stay one step ahead of enemies. Gain the ability to select Classical Primal Cards on level up and the following features:<br><br>Your mastery of Classical melodies have allowed your melodies to peak in an inspiring Crescendo. Allies who participate in your Strategy cards heal for half your Spell Power when the conditions are met, and the Strategy card's effect is Heightened.<br><br>Years of playing in tune with others has allowed you to tune into the rhythm of battle. You start each combat round with +2 Ability Points.<br><br>Modern melodies are unpredictable and can sound discordant to the untrained ear. This unpredictability and discordance can cause chaos among enemies and bolster your allies. Gain the ability to select Modern Primal Cards on level up and the following features:<br><br>Many say that the notes that aren't played as just as the important as the notes that you play. Add +1 Spell Power to the effect of your next Melody card for each non Melody card you played this combat round.<br><br>Enemies struggle to follow the complex beat of your melodies and leave openings for attack. After being hit by an Offensive Melody, enemies have their Defence Rating reduced by 1 for one round.<br><br>Experimental melodies are aggressive, loud and fast paced. These melodies bolster your and your allies attacks and deal huge damage. Gain the ability to select Experimental Primal Cards on level up and the following features:<br><br>You know how to command a presence on stage, and this shows on the battlefield. Enemies that are affected by your melodies focus their attention on you, for 1 round their Attack Power and Spell Power are reduced by half if they attack other targets.<br><br>Years of performing in full costume and carrying heavy gear have<br>
conditioned your physique. You gain the ability to wear Medium and Heavy Armour.<br><br>Your countless hours spent amid the chaos of mosh pits has given you an uncanny focus in any environment. You can cast Spells with no negative effects while Threatened.]]></description><link>classes/bard/subclasses.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Bard/Subclasses.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:39:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Druid<br><br>Druids share a close affinity with Nature and are able to draw on its powers to soothe their allies wounds, ensnare enemies and even take the form of powerful Beasts.<br><br>Faith<br><br>
<br>Strength
<br>Dexterity
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>Light Armour
<br>Medium Armour
<br><br>
<br>Staves
<br><br>Idol<br><br>
<br>Nature
<br><br><br>Your affinity with Nature has given you a deep understanding of the natural world. You start as an Expert in Nature, and your Defence Rating and Spell Power are increased by +1 while in the Wilds. <br><br>Animals see you as your kin, you gain the ability Speak to Animals: You can communicate with willing Animals. Feral animals will need to be calmed before they are willing to communicate. You also can add +2 to your Nature roll when trying to Persuade or Deceive an Animal.]]></description><link>classes/druid/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Druid/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:41:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Class Details - OLD]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Druids share a close affinity with Nature and are able to draw on its powers to soothe their allies wounds, ensnare enemies and even take the form of powerful Beasts.<br>Primary Stat: Faith<br>
Recommended Secondary Stats: Strength, Dexterity, Stamina<br>
Armour Specializations: Light and Medium Armour<br>
Weapon Specializations: Staves<br>
Damage Source: Idol<br>
Primal Card Types: Nature<br><br>Naturalist: Your affinity with Nature has given you a deep understanding of the natural world. You start as an Expert in Nature, and your Defence Rating and Spell Power are increased by +1 while in the Wilds.<br>
Animal Kinship: Animals see you as your kin, you gain the ability Speak to Animals: You can communicate with willing Animals. Feral animals will need to be calmed before they are willing to communicate. You also can add +2 to your Nature roll when trying to Persuade or Deceive an Animal.<br><br>Druids can choose to build an affinity with specific aspects of Nature. Select one of the following:<br>Botanist: Botanists have an affinity for all things that grow in the natural world. They can call upon the rejuvenating powers of water to heal allies and unleash the forces of the Wilds on enemies.  Gain the following features:<br>
Renewing Waters: Your deep understanding of the role of water in nature has allowed you to focus its renewing qualities to a high degree. Nature Healing Cards are heightened and you gain +1 Spell Power when casting them in the Wilds.<br>
Micro Biome: You bring the forces of Nature with you wherever you go. Once per encounter, can spend 2 Ability Points to create the Biome of your choice. Biomes have a radius of 60ft and last 10 minutes. Biomes:<br>
Forest: Create a Forest biome, surrounding the field with trees and entangling vines. Enemies in your biome treat this area as difficult terrain.<br>
Desert: Create a barren landscape of sand and dunes. All enemies in this biome suffer from Heat Exhaustion: If you spent your last combat round in this biome, you lose 1 Action Point.<br>
Wetland: Create a marshy wetland, with pools of stagnant water and an abundance of biting insects. Enemies in this biome struggle to ward off the swarms of biting insects and have their Nature Resistance reduced by 1<br>
Exponential Growth: Plants and trees around your grow with renewed vigour. Botany Spells gain an bonus of half your Spell Power. <br>Stargazer: Stargazer druids are master planners that draw inspiration of the constellations. They also rely on the Sun and the Moon to enhance their powers. Gain the following features:<br> Sun &amp; Moon: Stargazer druid's power's ebb and flow with cycle of day and night. They gain a different bonus depending on the time of day:<br>
<br>Solar Flare: During the day, you are empowered by the immense energy of the Sun. Damaging Nature spells can consume additional Action Points when cast, add +1 Spell Power per Action point.
<br>Lunar Cycle: During the night you embody the balance and poise of the Moon. Each Spell Card you play advances the phase of the moon, starting with the Waxing Phase: Crescent, Half Moon, Gibbous, and Full Moon. Upon reaching Full Moon your next Nature spell is heightened and gains +2 Spell Power. After reaching Full Moon, the Moon will enter the Waning Phase: Gibbous, Half Moon, Crescent, New Moon.<br>
Astral Seer: Stargazer druid's have learned to read the threads of fate that are woven by the stars above. Once per day they can play a Strategy card, and instantly trigger its effect without having met the conditions.
<br>Idea: Later class features: Solar Eclipse, Lunar Eclipse. Allows the druid to temporarily gain either Solar Flare or Lunar Cycle.<br>Therian Devotee: Therian Devotees have largely abandoned their humanity and bound their souls to a Great Spirit, giving them animal traits and even allowing them to become an Avatar of their Great Spirit. Gain the following features:<br>Return to Nature: Therian Devotees reject the implements of society and cannot wield weapons or wear armour. <br>Spirit Bound: Therian druids bind themselves to a Great Spirit, gaining some of their traits and the ability to take on the form of their Avatar. Select a Great Spirit:<br>
<br>Muhgwal, Ursine Champion: 

<br>Ursine Vigour: Your binding has blessed you with a small portion of Muhgwal's legendary constitution. Your Stamina modifier increases to (.4), and your Defence Rating now scales with your Attack Power.
<br>Strength of Muhgwal: Embody Muhgwal's mighty strength of spirit. Casting Nature spells will use half your Attack Power or Spell Power, whichever is higher.
<br>Avatar of Muhgwal: Take on the form of your spirit's avatar, a large bear who's appearance can be derived from the Player's Character:

<br>You can only cast spells that have the Beast trait, but you can use your full Attack Power instead of Spell Power.
<br>Gain half your HP as bonus HP
<br>Your basic attack becomes Maul: D6
<br>You are Resistant +1 to physical damage


<br>Lu'Wan, Divine Claw of Tavir:

<br>Feline Grace: Your reflexes become sharpened and your agility blessed by Lu'Wan. Your Defence rating becomes half your Attack Power, and your attacks and abilities can now Critically Strike. Your Dexterity modifier increases to (.3) for Attack Power
<br>Agile Caster: Your newfound agility has let you find new ways to channel the powers of Nature. Casting Nature spells will use half your Attack Power or Spell Power, whichever is higher.
<br>Avatar of Lu'Wan: take on the form of your spirit's avatar, a fearsome Tiger who's appearance can be derived from the Player's Character:

<br>You can only cast spells that have the Beast trait, but can use your full Attack Power instead of Spell Power. These spells can also Critically Strike.
<br>Gain +1 Attack Power and +10ft of movements speed.
<br>Your basic attack becomes Sharpened Claws: D8
<br>Your physical attacks and abilities gain the effect Lacerate: On a successful attack, your target bleeding for 3 turns. Bleeding: targets take 1 Attack Power of damage at the beginning of each turn.
<br>You gain the innate ability Pounce: Once per combat round spend up to 25ft of movement to Pounce on a target, avoiding difficult terrain and possibly knocking the target prone. 




<br>Wahula, Eyes of the True Seer:

<br>Wahula's Legacy: Binding yourself to Wahula has allowed you to glimpse a small part of the Truth of the Universe allowing you to see opportunities others cannot. Your Card Pool increases to 6.
<br>Prophesize: Attempt to predict your fate, during daily preparations randomly draw 3 cards from your Deck and place them face down in your reserve. Once per combat round you can play one blindly, ignoring the Action Point cost. If the card is not playable, discard it with no effect. If it is playable, increase the Spell Power by half.
<br>Avatar of Wahula: Take on the form of your avatar, becoming an astral version of yourself with the wings of an owl:

<br>Your movement speed increases by 10ft and becomes flying.
<br>Your Spell Power increases by +1
<br>Gain the ability Piercing Gaze: Once per combat round, select one target and reduce their Nature Resistance by 1.
<br>






]]></description><link>classes/druid/class-details-old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Druid/Class Details - OLD.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 16:59:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Subclasses]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Druids can choose to build an affinity with specific aspects of Nature. Select one of the following:<br>Botanist: Botanists have an affinity for all things that grow in the natural world. They can call upon the rejuvenating powers of water to heal allies and unleash the forces of the Wilds on enemies.  Gain the following features:<br>
Renewing Waters: Your deep understanding of the role of water in nature has allowed you to focus its renewing qualities to a high degree. Nature Healing Cards are heightened and you gain +1 Spell Power when casting them in the Wilds.<br>
Micro Biome: You bring the forces of Nature with you wherever you go. Once per encounter, can spend 2 Ability Points to create the Biome of your choice. Biomes have a radius of 60ft and last 10 minutes. Biomes:<br>
Forest: Create a Forest biome, surrounding the field with trees and entangling vines. Enemies in your biome treat this area as difficult terrain.<br>
Desert: Create a barren landscape of sand and dunes. All enemies in this biome suffer from Heat Exhaustion: If you spent your last combat round in this biome, you lose 1 Action Point.<br>
Wetland: Create a marshy wetland, with pools of stagnant water and an abundance of biting insects. Enemies in this biome struggle to ward off the swarms of biting insects and have their Nature Resistance reduced by 1<br>
Exponential Growth: Plants and trees around your grow with renewed vigour. Botany Spells gain an bonus of half your Spell Power. <br>Stargazer: Stargazer druids are master planners that draw inspiration of the constellations. They also rely on the Sun and the Moon to enhance their powers. Gain the following features:<br> Sun &amp; Moon: Stargazer druid's power's ebb and flow with cycle of day and night. They gain a different bonus depending on the time of day:<br>
<br>Solar Flare: During the day, you are empowered by the immense energy of the Sun. Damaging Nature spells can consume additional Action Points when cast, add +1 Spell Power per Action point.
<br>Lunar Cycle: During the night you embody the balance and poise of the Moon. Each Spell Card you play advances the phase of the moon, starting with the Waxing Phase: Crescent, Half Moon, Gibbous, and Full Moon. Upon reaching Full Moon your next Nature spell is heightened and gains +2 Spell Power. After reaching Full Moon, the Moon will enter the Waning Phase: Gibbous, Half Moon, Crescent, New Moon.<br>
Astral Seer: Stargazer druid's have learned to read the threads of fate that are woven by the stars above. Once per day they can play a Strategy card, and instantly trigger its effect without having met the conditions.
<br>Idea: Later class features: Solar Eclipse, Lunar Eclipse. Allows the druid to temporarily gain either Solar Flare or Lunar Cycle.<br>Therian Devotee: Therian Devotees have largely abandoned their humanity and bound their souls to a Great Spirit, giving them animal traits and even allowing them to become an Avatar of their Great Spirit. Gain the following features:<br>Return to Nature: Therian Devotees reject the implements of society and cannot wield weapons or wear armour. <br>Spirit Bound: Therian druids bind themselves to a Great Spirit, gaining some of their traits and the ability to take on the form of their Avatar. Select a Great Spirit:<br>
<br>Muhgwal, Ursine Champion: 

<br>Ursine Vigour: Your binding has blessed you with a small portion of Muhgwal's legendary constitution. Your Stamina modifier increases to (.4), and your Defence Rating now scales with your Attack Power.
<br>Strength of Muhgwal: Embody Muhgwal's mighty strength of spirit. Casting Nature spells will use half your Attack Power or Spell Power, whichever is higher.
<br>Avatar of Muhgwal: Take on the form of your spirit's avatar, a large bear who's appearance can be derived from the Player's Character:

<br>You can only cast spells that have the Beast trait, but you can use your full Attack Power instead of Spell Power.
<br>Gain half your HP as bonus HP
<br>Your basic attack becomes Maul: D6
<br>You are Resistant +1 to physical damage


<br>Lu'Wan, Divine Claw of Tavir:

<br>Feline Grace: Your reflexes become sharpened and your agility blessed by Lu'Wan. Your Defence rating becomes half your Attack Power, and your attacks and abilities can now Critically Strike. Your Dexterity modifier increases to (.3) for Attack Power
<br>Agile Caster: Your newfound agility has let you find new ways to channel the powers of Nature. Casting Nature spells will use half your Attack Power or Spell Power, whichever is higher.
<br>Avatar of Lu'Wan: take on the form of your spirit's avatar, a fearsome Tiger who's appearance can be derived from the Player's Character:

<br>You can only cast spells that have the Beast trait, but can use your full Attack Power instead of Spell Power. These spells can also Critically Strike.
<br>Gain +1 Attack Power and +10ft of movements speed.
<br>Your basic attack becomes Sharpened Claws: D8
<br>Your physical attacks and abilities gain the effect Lacerate: On a successful attack, your target bleeding for 3 turns. Bleeding: targets take 1 Attack Power of damage at the beginning of each turn.
<br>You gain the innate ability Pounce: Once per combat round spend up to 25ft of movement to Pounce on a target, avoiding difficult terrain and possibly knocking the target prone. 




<br>Wahula, Eyes of the True Seer:

<br>Wahula's Legacy: Binding yourself to Wahula has allowed you to glimpse a small part of the Truth of the Universe allowing you to see opportunities others cannot. Your Card Pool increases to 6.
<br>Prophesize: Attempt to predict your fate, during daily preparations randomly draw 3 cards from your Deck and place them face down in your reserve. Once per combat round you can play one blindly, ignoring the Action Point cost. If the card is not playable, discard it with no effect. If it is playable, increase the Spell Power by half.
<br>Avatar of Wahula: Take on the form of your avatar, becoming an astral version of yourself with the wings of an owl:

<br>Your movement speed increases by 10ft and becomes flying.
<br>Your Spell Power increases by +1
<br>Gain the ability Piercing Gaze: Once per combat round, select one target and reduce their Nature Resistance by 1.
<br>






]]></description><link>classes/druid/subclasses.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Druid/Subclasses.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:42:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Elementalist<br><br>Alchemists power both in and out of combat comes largely from their mastery of potions, tonics, bombs and 'perfumes'.<br><br>Intellect<br><br>
<br>Charisma
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>None
<br><br>
<br>Staves
<br><br>Elemental Focus<br><br>
<br>Elemental
<br><br><br>Your mastery of the elements has made you resistant to their powers. Gain 1 Resistant Rating against Elemental Damage.<br><br>You can become attuned to an elemental damage type, increasing your mastery with these spells. When casting spells of your attuned type, their Spell Power is increased by half and are able to Critically Strike.<br><br>You harness your powers to create a barrier out of your attuned element. Gain the innate ability (Your attuned Element) Bulwark: Create a defensive barrier that increases your Defence Rating to half of your Spell Power. Attackers take 1 Spell Power of your attuned elemental damage type when they land an attack against you. Lasts until long rest or is removed by another ability.]]></description><link>classes/elementalist/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Elementalist/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:45:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Class Details - OLD]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Elementalists are powerful sorcerers who channel the immense power of the elements to tear apart the battlefield.<br>Primary Stat: Intellect<br>
Recommended Secondary Stats: Charisma, Stamina<br>
Armour Specializations: None<br>
Weapon Specializations: Staves<br>
Damage Source: Elemental Focus<br>
Primal Card Types: Elemental<br><br>Master of the Elements: Your mastery of the elements has made you resistant to their powers. Gain 1 Resistant Rating against Elemental Damage.<br>Elemental Attunement:  You can become attuned to an elemental damage type, increasing your mastery with these spells. When casting spells of your attuned type, their Spell Power is increased by half and are able to Critically Strike.<br>Elemental Bulwark: You harness your powers to create a barrier out of your attuned element. Gain the innate ability (Your attuned Element) Bulwark: Create a defensive barrier that increases your Defence Rating to half of your Spell Power. Attackers take 1 Spell Power of your attuned elemental damage type when they land an attack against you. Lasts until long rest or is removed by another ability.]]></description><link>classes/elementalist/class-details-old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Elementalist/Class Details - OLD.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:40:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Martialist<br><br>Martialist are masters of Martial combat --  from advanced weapon training to hand to hand combat they are unmatched in melee combat.<br><br>Strength or Dexterity<br><br>
<br>Faith
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>Light Armour
<br>Medium Armour
<br><br>
<br>Simple Weapons
<br>Martial Weapons
<br>Light Crossbows
<br>Light Bows
<br>Shields
<br><br>Equipped Weapon<br><br>
<br>Martial
<br><br><br>Martialists can find even the small openings in battle, allowing them to use Weapon Attacks as a Reaction.<br><br>Veterans of countless battles, Martialists gain increased focus when facing multiple enemies. Gain +1 Attack Power and +1 Defence Rating when 2 or more enemies are in melee range.]]></description><link>classes/martialist/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Martialist/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:48:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Class Details - OLD]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Martialist are masters of Martial combat --  from advanced weapon training to hand to hand combat they are unmatched in melee combat.<br>Primary Stat: Strength or Dexterity<br>
Recommended Secondary Stats: Stamina, Faith<br>
Armour Specializations: Medium and Heavy Armour<br>
Weapon Specializations: Simple Weapons, Martial Weapons, Light Bows, Hand Crossbows, Shields<br>
Damage Source: Equipped Weapon<br>
Primal Card Types: Martial<br><br>Opportunists: Martialists can find even the small openings in battle, allowing them to use Weapon Attacks as a Reaction.<br>In the Fray: Veterans of countless battles, Martialists gain increased focus when facing multiple enemies. Gain +1 Attack Power and +1 Defence Rating when 2 or more enemies are in melee range.<br>Martial Vocation: Martialists are able to specialize in a variety of combat styles, select one of the following:<br>The Way of the Fist: Way of the Fist Martialists can go toe to toe with even the most fearsome enemies with nothing but their fists. They can navigate the field with uncanny agility, dismantling targets with flurries of attacks. You gain the ability to select Martial: Way of the Fist Primal cards on level up.<br>
Dexterous Combatant: You have come to rely on your well honed reflexes to avoid enemy attacks. When not wearing armour, your Defence Rating is equal to your Dexterity Modifier. Your Dexterity modifier also increases to '.3'.<br>
Lethal Weapons: Your fists must be registered with the proper authorities, as they are lethal weapons. Your Unarmed attacks now use a D6 damage die and scale with your Belt. Belt: Your belt represents your current level of training on your journey to become a Way of the Fist Master. Having graduated from your early training, you have been awarded with the 'Acolyte's Cord', a simple but dignified length of tightly woven hemp cord.<br>
Successive Strikes: Your fighting style emphasizes chaining together rapid fire strikes to create devastating combos. Each successive strike you land in the combat round builds your Combo Points up to a maximum of 5 (Critical Strikes add 2 Combo Points). Combo Points can be spent on Combo Breaker cards, the effect will vary depending on the number of points spent. <br>Berserker: Berserkers are tribal warriors who thrive in the fury of battle, giving into to their bloodlust to become unstoppable killing machines. You gain the ability to select Berserker Primal Cards on level up and the following features:<br>
Bloodlust: You give in to the frenzy of battle, letting Bloodlust build and empower your attacks and increase your capacity for pain. Each time you take or deal damage gain 1 Point of Bloodlust (Gain 2 on Critical Strikes dealt or received) up to a maximum of 6. Gain +1 Attack Power and +1 Defence Rating for every 3 Bloodlust points you currently have. Berserker Primal Cards will have additional effects that be activated by consuming Bloodlust points.<br>
Drenched in Blood: Many years of tribal combat have conditioned your body and mind, increasing your capacity for pain and reducing your dependency on Armour. While not wearing Amour, your Defence Rating now scales with your Strength and your Stamina Modifier is increased to (.4)<br>
Tribal Roots: Your tribal roots have influenced your fighting style, pick one of the following:<br>
Plains Tribe:  Combat in the open plains often involved mounted enemies and large scale battles. This has given you an increase proficiency with Great Weapons, Spears and Javelins. Gain +1 Attack Power when wielding these weapons.<br>
Forest Tribe: Fighting in the narrow confines of the woods has given you an affinity for close quarters combat. You have increased proficiency with 1 Handed Swords, Fist Weapons, and Hand Crossbows. Gain +1 Attack Power when wielding these weapons.<br>
Tribal Duellist: You came from a strong tribal tradition of honour duels and single combat. Due to the crowd pleasing nature of these duels, you have mastered the art of dual wielding. You can dual wield non-finesse 1 handed weapons, and your Dual Wield penalty is reduced to (.3). Idea - Late game feature Titan's Grip: Gain the ability to dual wield great weapons at reduced damage.<br>Tactician: Tacticians are famed battle commanders who use their mastery of tactics to control the battlefield and inspire their allies. You gain the ability to select Tactician Primal Cards on level up and gain the following features:<br>
Brutal Strategist: Your experience in war has taught you to break your enemies morale with a swift and brutal efficiency. All of your strategy cards are Heightened and once per encounter you can play a Strategy cards and instantly trigger its effect without having met the conditions.<br>
Commander's Rapport: Your allies recognize your air of authority and respect your combat prowess. After triggering a Strategy card, you and your allies gain +1 Attack Power and +1 Defence rating until the end of the next combat round.<br>
Leading the Charge: You fearlessly lead the charge into battle, inspiring those around you and demoralizing enemies you attack. You and your allies within 15ft gain 10ft of movement speed when moving towards enemies. On a successful attack, your enemies Attack Power is reduce by 1 until the end of the combat round.<br>
Legacies of War: You draw on your past experiences to influence your combat style:<br>
Battlefield Commander: You commanded vast legions of soldiers and excel when dealing with large scale combat. You gain the trait Absolute Authority: Allies who participate in your strategy cards gain +2 ability points on the next combat round after the strategy is triggered.<br>
Skirmisher: You led small bands of elite soldiers and employed hit and run tactics to overcome impossible odds in battle. Allies who participate in your strategy cards gain the trait Skirmisher for the next 3 combat rounds after the strategy is executed. Skirmisher:  After<br>
]]></description><link>classes/martialist/class-details-old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Martialist/Class Details - OLD.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:38:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Subclasses]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Martial Vocation: Martialists are able to specialize in a variety of combat styles, select one of the following:<br>The Way of the Fist: Way of the Fist Martialists can go toe to toe with even the most fearsome enemies with nothing but their fists. They can navigate the field with uncanny agility, dismantling targets with flurries of attacks. You gain the ability to select Martial: Way of the Fist Primal cards on level up.<br>
Dexterous Combatant: You have come to rely on your well honed reflexes to avoid enemy attacks. When not wearing armour, your Defence Rating is equal to your Dexterity Modifier. Your Dexterity modifier also increases to '.3'.<br>
Lethal Weapons: Your fists must be registered with the proper authorities, as they are lethal weapons. Your Unarmed attacks now use a D6 damage die and scale with your Belt. Belt: Your belt represents your current level of training on your journey to become a Way of the Fist Master. Having graduated from your early training, you have been awarded with the 'Acolyte's Cord', a simple but dignified length of tightly woven hemp cord.<br>
Successive Strikes: Your fighting style emphasizes chaining together rapid fire strikes to create devastating combos. Each successive strike you land in the combat round builds your Combo Points up to a maximum of 5 (Critical Strikes add 2 Combo Points). Combo Points can be spent on Combo Breaker cards, the effect will vary depending on the number of points spent. <br>Berserker: Berserkers are tribal warriors who thrive in the fury of battle, giving into to their bloodlust to become unstoppable killing machines. You gain the ability to select Berserker Primal Cards on level up and the following features:<br>
Bloodlust: You give in to the frenzy of battle, letting Bloodlust build and empower your attacks and increase your capacity for pain. Each time you take or deal damage gain 1 Point of Bloodlust (Gain 2 on Critical Strikes dealt or received) up to a maximum of 6. Gain +1 Attack Power and +1 Defence Rating for every 3 Bloodlust points you currently have. Berserker Primal Cards will have additional effects that be activated by consuming Bloodlust points.<br>
Drenched in Blood: Many years of tribal combat have conditioned your body and mind, increasing your capacity for pain and reducing your dependency on Armour. While not wearing Amour, your Defence Rating now scales with your Strength and your Stamina Modifier is increased to (.4)<br>
Tribal Roots: Your tribal roots have influenced your fighting style, pick one of the following:<br>
Plains Tribe:  Combat in the open plains often involved mounted enemies and large scale battles. This has given you an increase proficiency with Great Weapons, Spears and Javelins. Gain +1 Attack Power when wielding these weapons.<br>
Forest Tribe: Fighting in the narrow confines of the woods has given you an affinity for close quarters combat. You have increased proficiency with 1 Handed Swords, Fist Weapons, and Hand Crossbows. Gain +1 Attack Power when wielding these weapons.<br>
Tribal Duellist: You came from a strong tribal tradition of honour duels and single combat. Due to the crowd pleasing nature of these duels, you have mastered the art of dual wielding. You can dual wield non-finesse 1 handed weapons, and your Dual Wield penalty is reduced to (.3). Idea - Late game feature Titan's Grip: Gain the ability to dual wield great weapons at reduced damage.<br>Tactician: Tacticians are famed battle commanders who use their mastery of tactics to control the battlefield and inspire their allies. You gain the ability to select Tactician Primal Cards on level up and gain the following features:<br>
Brutal Strategist: Your experience in war has taught you to break your enemies morale with a swift and brutal efficiency. All of your strategy cards are Heightened and once per encounter you can play a Strategy cards and instantly trigger its effect without having met the conditions.<br>
Commander's Rapport: Your allies recognize your air of authority and respect your combat prowess. After triggering a Strategy card, you and your allies gain +1 Attack Power and +1 Defence rating until the end of the next combat round.<br>
Leading the Charge: You fearlessly lead the charge into battle, inspiring those around you and demoralizing enemies you attack. You and your allies within 15ft gain 10ft of movement speed when moving towards enemies. On a successful attack, your enemies Attack Power is reduce by 1 until the end of the combat round.<br>
Legacies of War: You draw on your past experiences to influence your combat style:<br>
Battlefield Commander: You commanded vast legions of soldiers and excel when dealing with large scale combat. You gain the trait Absolute Authority: Allies who participate in your strategy cards gain +2 ability points on the next combat round after the strategy is triggered.<br>
Skirmisher: You led small bands of elite soldiers and employed hit and run tactics to overcome impossible odds in battle. Allies who participate in your strategy cards gain the trait Skirmisher for the next 3 combat rounds after the strategy is executed. Skirmisher:  After]]></description><link>classes/martialist/subclasses.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Martialist/Subclasses.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:49:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Priest<br><br>Priests draw power from their Divine connections, channelling that power to torment their enemies or soothe the wounds of their allies.<br><br>Faith<br><br>
<br>Charisma
<br>Intellect
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>None 
<br><br>
<br>Staves
<br>Sigils
<br><br>Divine Symbol<br><br>
<br>Good
<br>Neutral
<br>Evil
<br><br><br>Priests must complete their Daily Prayer, gaining a blessing from their God and gain the ability Divine Evocation.<br><br>Once per day, heighten the effect of your God's blessing. ]]></description><link>classes/priest/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Priest/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:52:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Class Details - OLD]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Priests draw power from their Divine connections, channelling that power to torment their enemies or soothe the wounds of their allies.<br>Primary Stat: Faith<br>
Recommended Secondary Stats: Charisma, Intellect, Stamina<br>
Armour Specializations: None<br>
Weapon Specializations: Staves, Sigils<br>
Damage Source: Divine Symbol<br>
Primal Card Types: Good, Neutral, Evil<br><br>Daily Prayer - Priests must complete their Daily Prayer, gaining a blessing from their God and gain the ability Divine Evocation.<br>
Divine Evocation: Once per day, heighten the effect of your God's blessing. <br>Divine Worship - Priests spend most of their lives worshipping a Divine Being, this Divine Being determines the types of spells that they has access to. Pick one of the following:<br>Levelyn - The Godess of Light and Renewal, allows the Priest to learn Light and Radiant Spells that have immense healing power and can deal devastating damage to the Evil creatures and beings. Followers of Levelyn gain Blessing of Light from their Daily Prayer.<br>
Blessing of Light: The Priest radiates a faint light, any ally within a 30ft radius gains 5 Resistance to Evil damage types.  Evocation: Reaction - Add your Spell Power Value to this Resistance value.<br>Anarius - The God of Justice and Order, allows the Priest to learn Light and Radiant Spells that bolster Defence, empower allies and deal massive damage to Evil creatures and beings. Followers of Anarius gain Crusader's Aura from their Daily Prayer.<br>
Crusader's Aura: The Priest embodies the might of Divine Justice, any ally within 30ft that receives damage in the last round can add 2 Radiant damage to their Melee and Ranged weapon attacks. Evocation: Focus your fury into a single devastating Holy smite, dealing 1D8 Radiant damage for each ally that took damage in the last round. <br>Sulon - The God of Balance, allows the Priest to learn Light and Shadow spells that restore your ally's HP while dealing damage. Followers of Sulon can gain either Blessing of Dawn or Blessing of Dusk from their Daily Prayer.<br>
Blessing of Dawn: Empowers the Priest's healing and defensive spells. Add one additional Dice to your Spell Power when casting Defence or Healing Spells.  Evocation: Once per Day you can double your Spell Power on a Defence of Healing Spell.<br>
Blessing of Dusk: Empowers the Priest's damaging and mind warping spells. Add one additional Dice to your Spell Power when casting Spell Attacks and Charm Effects. Evocation: Once per day you can double your Spell Power on a Spell Attack or Charm Effect.<br>Vardin - The God of Death, allows the Priest to learn Shadow spells that leech the vitality of others and create fear and panic among their enemies.  Followers of Vardin become bound by a Vow of Solemnity during their daily prayer.<br>
Vow of Solemnity: The Priest cannot speak, yet allies around them have their minds put at ease, becoming immune to Fear effects. Any ally within 30ft that makes a Death Saving Throw does so at advantage. Evocation: Once per day, inflict Mortal Terror on all enemies within 60ft.<br>
Mortal Terror: Targets become acutely aware of their impending death, they cannot use Reactions until the end of the combat round and become Vulnerable to Shadow Damage.<br>Ghanrak - The God of Pestilence, allows the Priest to learn Shadow and Chaos Spells that deal ramping damage over time and sap the strength of the afflicted. Followers of Ghanrak gain the blessing Envoy of Decay.<br>
Envoy of Decay: Embody the force of disease and decay, damage over time effects that deal Evil damage gain one Spell Power Dice for each enemy to which they spread. Evocation:  Once per day you can cast Mass Contagion - Spread one active Damage Over Time effect to all nearby enemies within 15ft. ]]></description><link>classes/priest/class-details-old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Priest/Class Details - OLD.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 18:06:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Subclasses]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Divine Worship - Priests spend most of their lives worshipping a Divine Being, this Divine Being determines the types of spells that they has access to. Pick one of the following:<br>Levelyn - The Godess of Light and Renewal, allows the Priest to learn Light and Radiant Spells that have immense healing power and can deal devastating damage to the Evil creatures and beings. Followers of Levelyn gain Blessing of Light from their Daily Prayer.<br>
Blessing of Light: The Priest radiates a faint light, any ally within a 30ft radius gains 5 Resistance to Evil damage types.  Evocation: Reaction - Add your Spell Power Value to this Resistance value.<br>Anarius - The God of Justice and Order, allows the Priest to learn Light and Radiant Spells that bolster Defence, empower allies and deal massive damage to Evil creatures and beings. Followers of Anarius gain Crusader's Aura from their Daily Prayer.<br>
Crusader's Aura: The Priest embodies the might of Divine Justice, any ally within 30ft that receives damage in the last round can add 2 Radiant damage to their Melee and Ranged weapon attacks. Evocation: Focus your fury into a single devastating Holy smite, dealing 1D8 Radiant damage for each ally that took damage in the last round. <br>Sulon - The God of Balance, allows the Priest to learn Light and Shadow spells that restore your ally's HP while dealing damage. Followers of Sulon can gain either Blessing of Dawn or Blessing of Dusk from their Daily Prayer.<br>
Blessing of Dawn: Empowers the Priest's healing and defensive spells. Add one additional Dice to your Spell Power when casting Defence or Healing Spells.  Evocation: Once per Day you can double your Spell Power on a Defence of Healing Spell.<br>
Blessing of Dusk: Empowers the Priest's damaging and mind warping spells. Add one additional Dice to your Spell Power when casting Spell Attacks and Charm Effects. Evocation: Once per day you can double your Spell Power on a Spell Attack or Charm Effect.<br>Vardin - The God of Death, allows the Priest to learn Shadow spells that leech the vitality of others and create fear and panic among their enemies.  Followers of Vardin become bound by a Vow of Solemnity during their daily prayer.<br>
Vow of Solemnity: The Priest cannot speak, yet allies around them have their minds put at ease, becoming immune to Fear effects. Any ally within 30ft that makes a Death Saving Throw does so at advantage. Evocation: Once per day, inflict Mortal Terror on all enemies within 60ft.<br>
Mortal Terror: Targets become acutely aware of their impending death, they cannot use Reactions until the end of the combat round and become Vulnerable to Shadow Damage.<br>Ghanrak - The God of Pestilence, allows the Priest to learn Shadow and Chaos Spells that deal ramping damage over time and sap the strength of the afflicted. Followers of Ghanrak gain the blessing Envoy of Decay.<br>
Envoy of Decay: Embody the force of disease and decay, damage over time effects that deal Evil damage gain one Spell Power Dice for each enemy to which they spread. Evocation:  Once per day you can cast Mass Contagion - Spread one active Damage Over Time effect to all nearby enemies within 15ft. ]]></description><link>classes/priest/subclasses.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Priest/Subclasses.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:53:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Ranger<br><br>Rangers are versatile combatants who combine their marksmanship ability and guile to making leave enemies feeling helpless as their companions are picked off.<br><br>Dexterity<br><br>
<br>Faith
<br>Strength
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>Light Armour
<br><br>
<br>Finesse Weapons
<br>Ranged Weapons
<br>Martial Ranged Weapons
<br><br>Equipped Weapons<br><br>
<br>Marksmanship
<br><br><br>The Ranger's keen eyes and mastery of nature make them Experts in Survival.<br><br>Gain the ability Hunter's Mark: Select a target and mark them as your quarry. You gain +1 Attack Power against this target, and +1 Defence Rating when defending against them.<br><br>Your years of training have allowed you to switch between your Ranged and Melee weapon with uncanny speed and grace. Switching your equipped weapon no longer has any ability point cost.]]></description><link>classes/ranger/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Ranger/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:55:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Class Details - OLD]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Rangers are versatile combatants who combine their marksmanship ability and guile to making leave enemies feeling helpless as their companions are picked off.<br>Primary Stat: Dexterity<br>
Recommended Secondary Stats: Faith, Strength, Stamina<br>
Armour Specializations: Light Armour<br>
Weapon Specializations: Finesse Weapons, Ranged Weapons, Martial Ranged Weapons<br>
Damage Source: Equipped Weapon<br>
Primal Card Types: Marksmanship<br><br>Eagle Eyed: The Ranger's keen eyes and mastery of nature make them Experts in Survival.<br>
Hunter's Mark:  Gain the ability Hunter's Mark: Select a target and mark them as your quarry. You gain +1 Attack Power against this target, and +1 Defence Rating when defending against them.<br>
Practiced Hands: Your years of training have allowed you to switch between your Ranged and Melee weapon with uncanny speed and grace. Switching your equipped weapon no longer has any ability point cost.<br>Hunter's Path: Select one of the following Hunter's Path's:<br>Marksman:<br>
Marksman's mastery of their Ranged Weapon skills allow them to unleash devastating damage from great distances. They gain the following Features:<br>
Sniper: Your uncanny accuracy and skill has allowed you to to hit targets from great distances without sacrificing damage. Double the effective range of your equipped Ranged Weapon.<br>
Focused Shot: Your eye has become so finely tuned that you can spot weak points in armour at any distance. Gain 1 Armour Penetration against your Hunter's Mark target.<br>
Aspect of the Talon: Your attunement to martial weapons as elevated your ability to hit vital organs, increasing Critical Strike Chance by 1.5<br>Survivalist:<br>
Survivalists are jack of all trade combatants that use their environment, Traps, and balanced fighting skills to deftly navigate any encounter.<br>
Expert Trapper: Add your Attack Power to Trap damage.<br>
Martial Adept: Select a Martial Subtype, you can now add this Primal Card Type to your deck. You can also gain access to Martial Weapons.<br>
Aspect of the Wolf: Your study of pack tactics has elevated your combat prowess when fighting with allies. Gain a Strategy Card at levels: 1, 6, 11, 16, 20. When a Strategy card that you played has its conditions met, gain 2 additional Action Points on the next combat round.<br>Beast Master:<br>
Beast Master's share a close kinship with Nature and are able to bind Beasts to themselves. They are able to select Nature Primal Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
Beast Mastery: Gain the ability Tame Beast: You can attempt to tame a Beast up to your level. This Beast will be bound to you as a companion and fight along side you. Beasts each have their own individual abilities and attributes.<br>
Shared Vitality: Your bond with your companion transcends the mundane, damage you or your beast takes is divided evenly between you.<br>
Aspect of the Pack: You can use your bond with your companion to empower both your attacks. While within range (60ft), you both gain +1 Attack Power and +1 Defence Rating. This effect is lost if you or your Beast is unconcious. Once per day you can activate this effect to send your Beast into a frenzy - their Attack Power is doubled but their Defence Rating is Halved. ]]></description><link>classes/ranger/class-details-old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Ranger/Class Details - OLD.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 20:24:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Subclasses]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Hunter's Path: Select one of the following Hunter's Path's:<br>Marksman:<br>
Marksman's mastery of their Ranged Weapon skills allow them to unleash devastating damage from great distances. They gain the following Features:<br>
Sniper: Your uncanny accuracy and skill has allowed you to to hit targets from great distances without sacrificing damage. Double the effective range of your equipped Ranged Weapon.<br>
Focused Shot: Your eye has become so finely tuned that you can spot weak points in armour at any distance. Gain 1 Armour Penetration against your Hunter's Mark target.<br>
Aspect of the Talon: Your attunement to martial weapons as elevated your ability to hit vital organs, increasing Critical Strike Chance by 1.5<br>Survivalist:<br>
Survivalists are jack of all trade combatants that use their environment, Traps, and balanced fighting skills to deftly navigate any encounter.<br>
Expert Trapper: Add your Attack Power to Trap damage.<br>
Martial Adept: Select a Martial Subtype, you can now add this Primal Card Type to your deck. You can also gain access to Martial Weapons.<br>
Aspect of the Wolf: Your study of pack tactics has elevated your combat prowess when fighting with allies. Gain a Strategy Card at levels: 1, 6, 11, 16, 20. When a Strategy card that you played has its conditions met, gain 2 additional Action Points on the next combat round.<br>Beast Master:<br>
Beast Master's share a close kinship with Nature and are able to bind Beasts to themselves. They are able to select Nature Primal Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
Beast Mastery: Gain the ability Tame Beast: You can attempt to tame a Beast up to your level. This Beast will be bound to you as a companion and fight along side you. Beasts each have their own individual abilities and attributes.<br>
Shared Vitality: Your bond with your companion transcends the mundane, damage you or your beast takes is divided evenly between you.<br>
Aspect of the Pack: You can use your bond with your companion to empower both your attacks. While within range (60ft), you both gain +1 Attack Power and +1 Defence Rating. This effect is lost if you or your Beast is unconcious. Once per day you can activate this effect to send your Beast into a frenzy - their Attack Power is doubled but their Defence Rating is Halved. ]]></description><link>classes/ranger/subclasses.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Ranger/Subclasses.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:56:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Rogue<br><br>Rogues are masters of Subterfuge and are always looking for ways to sway combat in their favour. They are true believers that all is fair in love and war and are not bound to honourable combat.<br><br>Dexterity<br><br>
<br>Charisma
<br>Strength
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>Light Armour
<br><br>
<br>Simple Weapons
<br>Throwables
<br>Light Bows
<br>Hand Crossbows
<br><br>Equipped Weapon<br><br>
<br>Subterfuge
<br><br><br>Rogues use their guile to weave in and out of combat as needed. After landing a successful attack, the Rogue is able to move freely without giving the enemy a chance to use a Reaction.<br><br>Rogues will wait patiently for the perfect moment to strike, increasing the potency of their Critical Strike. Your Critical Strike Damage modifier is increased to x2.5<br><br>Rogues are masters of avoiding enemy detection and start as Experts in Stealth.]]></description><link>classes/rogue/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Rogue/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:58:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rogue]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>Rogues are masters of Subterfuge and are always looking for ways to sway combat in their favour. They are true believers that all is fair in love and war and are not bound to honourable combat.<br><br>Primary Stat: Dexterity<br>
Recommended Secondary Stats: [Strength, Stamina, Charisma, Faith]<br>
Armour Specializations: Light Armour<br>
Weapon Specializations: [Daggers, Short Swords, Throwables, Light Bows, Hand Crossbows]<br>
Damage Source: Equipped Weapon<br>
Primal Card Types: Subterfuge<br><br>Hit and Run: Rogues use their guile to weave in and out of combat as needed. After landing a successful attack, the Rogue is able to move freely without giving the enemy a chance to use a Reaction.<br>Opportunist:  Rogues will wait patiently for the perfect moment to strike, increasing the potency of their Critical Strike. Your Critical Strike Damage modifier is increased to x2.5<br>Master of the Shadows: Rogues are masters of avoiding enemy detection and start as Experts in Stealth.<br><br>Rogues can select one of 4 Specialties:<br><br>Rogues who specialize in Assassination use premeditated strikes and attack from the shadows to deal massive single target damage. They will be able to select Assassin Primal Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
<br>Unseen Strike: When attacking from while undetected your Critical Strike Chance is doubled.
<br>Lethal Poisons: You can access to lethal Poisons that can be applied to your weapons or thrown.
<br><br>Trickster Rogues are masters of illusion and trickery, confusing and picking apart enemy attackers. They are able to select Trickster Primal Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
<br>Force Magic Adept: You can add Force Cards to your deck. For damage, use your Spell Power Rating or half your Attack Power rating - whichever is higher.
<br>Illusory Double: You can summon an Illusory Double of yourself up to 30ft away. The double has half your HP, and will duplicate any attacks you make at half damage. They will also Threaten enemies and can use Reactions. Lasts up to 10 Minutes and can be used out of combat.
<br>####Swashbuckler<br>
Swarthy combatants who rely on Chance and bravado to take down their enemies. They are able to select Swashbuckler Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
<br>Roll the Bones: Gain a set of Basic Bone Dice that can be rolled to gain different modifiers. More powerful Bone Dice can be obtained throughout the world. 

<br>Basic Bone Dice: 

<br>1: Momentum - Gain 2 Action Points the first time you land an attack this turn
<br>2: Brazen Attacker - Add 1 Attack Power to your first successful attack this turn
<br>3: Evasive Maneuver - Add 1 Defence Rating to your next Defensive Action
<br>4: Feint - Your next attack is made as if the enemy was Threatened.
<br>5: Seize the Moment - Double the Critical Strike Chance of your next Attack
<br>6: Fleet Footwork - Gain 15ft of movement and avoid enemy Reactions until the end of your turn




<br>Where's the Rum?: After many years of fighting inebriated, you have come to rely on the effects of alcohol. While drunk you become harder to hit and your attacks are harder to predict, increasing your Defence Rating by 1 and gain 1 Armour Penetration. 
<br><br>Operators are mechanical masters who use Consumable, Traps and Equipment to turn the battlefield into a minefield. They are able to select Operator Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
<br>Gadget Specialist: Add your Attack Power to Equipment and Consumable damage. You can also Repair destroyed items between combats.
<br>Mastermind: Operators start as Experts in Engineering, and can select two Designs to master. Mastered designs require half the components to create, and unlocks their Mastery effect.
<br>Deep Pockets: Increase Consumable capacity to 5.
]]></description><link>classes/rogue/class-details-old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Rogue/Class Details - OLD.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 17:24:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Subclasses]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Rogues can select one of 4 Specialties:<br><br>Rogues who specialize in Assassination use premeditated strikes and attack from the shadows to deal massive single target damage. They will be able to select Assassin Primal Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
<br>Unseen Strike: When attacking from while undetected your Critical Strike Chance is doubled.
<br>Lethal Poisons: You can access to lethal Poisons that can be applied to your weapons or thrown.
<br><br>Trickster Rogues are masters of illusion and trickery, confusing and picking apart enemy attackers. They are able to select Trickster Primal Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
<br>Force Magic Adept: You can add Force Cards to your deck. For damage, use your Spell Power Rating or half your Attack Power rating - whichever is higher.
<br>Illusory Double: You can summon an Illusory Double of yourself up to 30ft away. The double has half your HP, and will duplicate any attacks you make at half damage. They will also Threaten enemies and can use Reactions. Lasts up to 10 Minutes and can be used out of combat.
<br>####Swashbuckler<br>
Swarthy combatants who rely on Chance and bravado to take down their enemies. They are able to select Swashbuckler Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
<br>Roll the Bones: Gain a set of Basic Bone Dice that can be rolled to gain different modifiers. More powerful Bone Dice can be obtained throughout the world. 

<br>Basic Bone Dice: 

<br>1: Momentum - Gain 2 Action Points the first time you land an attack this turn
<br>2: Brazen Attacker - Add 1 Attack Power to your first successful attack this turn
<br>3: Evasive Maneuver - Add 1 Defence Rating to your next Defensive Action
<br>4: Feint - Your next attack is made as if the enemy was Threatened.
<br>5: Seize the Moment - Double the Critical Strike Chance of your next Attack
<br>6: Fleet Footwork - Gain 15ft of movement and avoid enemy Reactions until the end of your turn




<br>Where's the Rum?: After many years of fighting inebriated, you have come to rely on the effects of alcohol. While drunk you become harder to hit and your attacks are harder to predict, increasing your Defence Rating by 1 and gain 1 Armour Penetration. 
<br><br>Operators are mechanical masters who use Consumable, Traps and Equipment to turn the battlefield into a minefield. They are able to select Operator Cards on level up and gain the following Features:<br>
<br>Gadget Specialist: Add your Attack Power to Equipment and Consumable damage. You can also Repair destroyed items between combats.
<br>Mastermind: Operators start as Experts in Engineering, and can select two Designs to master. Mastered designs require half the components to create, and unlocks their Mastery effect.
<br>Deep Pockets: Increase Consumable capacity to 5.
]]></description><link>classes/rogue/subclasses.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Rogue/Subclasses.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 13:59:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[name]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Warlock<br><br>Warlocks are casters who draw their power from a Demonic or Devilish Patron. Different Patrons can offer both advantages and disadvantages and this idea will be explored more later on.<br><br>Faith or Charisma<br><br>
<br>Intellect
<br>Stamina
<br><br>
<br>None
<br><br>
<br>Simple Weapons
<br><br>Effigy<br><br>
<br>Infernal
<br>Chaos
<br><br><br>Warlocks extensive study of the occult has endowed them with a strong understanding of Religions. Warlocks start as Experts in Religion. <br><br>Warlocks use their mastery of dark sorceries to bolster their defence, their Defence rating gains half their Spell Power when not wearing Armour. ]]></description><link>classes/warlock/class-details.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Warlock/Class Details.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:01:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Class Details - OLD]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Warlocks are casters who draw their power from a Demonic or Devilish Patron. Different Patrons can offer both advantages and disadvantages and this idea will be explored more later on.<br>Primary Stat: Faith or Charisma<br>
Recommended Secondary Stats: Charisma, Intellect, Stamina<br>
Armour Specializations: None<br>
Weapon Specializations: Simple Weapons (AP)<br>
Damage Source: Effigy<br>
Primal Card Types: Infernal, Chaos<br><br>Pick one of the following:<br>Demonic Enslavement - The Warlock has studied the dark sorceries that allow him to enslave lesser demons and syphon their power. Demon's are manifestations of pure chaos energy and can allow the Warlock to call on the powers of the Abyss. From summoning Demonic forces to assaulting the minds of their enemies, Demonic Warlocks are masters of creating chaos and despair among their enemies.<br>OR <br>Infernal Codex - The Warlock has become adept in the Infernal tongue and can negotiate pacts with Devil's to gain Infernal powers. Infernal magic is an incredibly destructive force, inflicting massive damage and binding their enemies with Devilish Pacts. Infernal Warlocks can decimate the battlefield, but may have conditions surrounding their Pact. <br>Other Features:<br>Occult Mastery - Warlocks extensive study of the occult has endowed them with a strong understanding of Religions. Warlocks start as Experts in Religion. <br>Bulwark of Shadows - Warlocks use their mastery of dark sorceries to bolster their defence, their Defence rating gains half their Spell Power when not wearing Armour. ]]></description><link>classes/warlock/class-details-old.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Warlock/Class Details - OLD.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 15:23:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Subclasses]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Pick one of the following:<br>Demonic Enslavement - The Warlock has studied the dark sorceries that allow him to enslave lesser demons and syphon their power. Demon's are manifestations of pure chaos energy and can allow the Warlock to call on the powers of the Abyss. From summoning Demonic forces to assaulting the minds of their enemies, Demonic Warlocks are masters of creating chaos and despair among their enemies.<br>OR <br>Infernal Codex - The Warlock has become adept in the Infernal tongue and can negotiate pacts with Devil's to gain Infernal powers. Infernal magic is an incredibly destructive force, inflicting massive damage and binding their enemies with Devilish Pacts. Infernal Warlocks can decimate the battlefield, but may have conditions surrounding their Pact. ]]></description><link>classes/warlock/subclasses.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Classes/Warlock/Subclasses.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 14:01:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Attributes & Skills]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>REWORKING FOR SIMPLICITY:<br>
<br>Base attributes will 1:1 represent combat power based on primary attributes. e.g.: 1 Strength = 1 Attack Power for a barbarian.
<br>Skills will have minimum stat requirements, or come with specific feats / items. These will be in no way directly derived from primary stats
<br>Hit points will still scale additionally on Stamina
<br>Tertiary attributes and critical strike will be gained purely through class feats and gear
<br>A large portion of feats will be locked behind primary stat requirements to maintain the flavour of each unique stat
<br><br>Strength - determines the characters physical strength and raw athletic ability. Directly increases attack power and may be required to equip certain Great Weapons.<br>Dexterity - determines the characters physical agility and reaction time. Can increase attack power with finesse weapons and critical strike chance.<br>Intellect - determines the players capability for wielding the raw forces of magic. Increases spell power and may be required to cast more powerful spells.<br>Faith - determines the strength of the players connection to divine beings. Increases spell power for faith based casters and allows characters to bind themself to more powerful beings.<br>Stamina - determines physical fitness and resilience to enemy attacks. Increases base health points, movement speed and may be required to wear heavier armor types. <br>Charisma - determines the players ability to influence other through deception, performance and persuasion. Also also increases spell power in healing magics and bolstering magics. <br>Values:<br>Each class has a modifier for how efficiently they use certain attributes. Simply multiply the attribute by this modifier to get your Secondary Attributes. Value's are always rounded up.<br>Example(s):<br>
The Elementalist class gains spell power from Intellect, with a class modifier of '.2'. So if the Elementalist has 15 Intellect, their spell power value will be 3. <br>The Weapon's Master class has a base modifier of '.2' for Stamina, but with the Sturdy feature this is increased to '.3'. So if the Weapon's Master has 12 Stamina, they will receive 4 HP per level. <br>Secondary Attributes:<br>
Secondary Attributes values are mostly inherited from Primary Attributes, but can be gained from certain equipment, consumables and spells.<br>Attack Power - The primary damage dealing attribute for physical damage dealers. The value determines the amount of dice rolled when dealing damage. The Damage Dice is determines by Class and equipment. Some attacks may specify a multiple of base attack power, such as half or double. Multiply the number of dice by this value and round up if necessary.<br>
Example: A Rogue with 11 Dexterity has 2 Attack Power, and is wielding a D6 Dagger. Therefore when an attack uses the Rogue's Attack Power, it would be rolled as 2D6. <br>Spell Power - The primary damage dealing attribute for spell casters. Functions in the same manner as Attack Power, though the damage Dice varies based on the caster.<br>
Example: Warlocks Damage Dice is determined by the power of their Patron, our Level 2 Warlock is currently using a Lesser Hellfire Demon with a D8 Dice. With 10 Intellect, and a Spell Power of 2, the Spell Power roll would be 2D8.<br>Hit Points - Hit points represent your characters physical and mental well being. Your character becomes Unconscious and gains the Dying trait when this value hits 0. Hit points are calculated by adding your modified Stamina value to your classes base HP.<br>
Example: A Druid with a base HP of 11, has 10 Stamina with a class modifier of '.3'. So at level 3 the Druid would have 23 HP.<br>Critical Strike - Critical Strike determines the chance of achieving a Critical Strike on an attack. Not all attacks or classes are capable of Critical Strikes. The value of this attribute is range that has to be rolled to achieve a Critical Strike.<br>
Example: A Rogue has a Critical Strike value of 7, so when rolling the D100 they need to roll a 93 or higher. <br>Defence Rating - Determines the number of Defence Dice rolled when called on by a Defensive Action. Works similarly to Attack Power and Spell Power.<br>
Example: A Range has a Defence Rating of 3 and is wearing Leather Armour with a D4 rating. When taking damage they would roll 3D4 to mitigate incoming damage.<br>Tertiary Attributes<br>
Tertiary Attributes are additional attributes most often gained from specialized equipment and class Features. These are highly limited but very powerful effects.<br>Armour Penetration - Bypass enemy armour, negating Defence Rating equal to the attribute value.<br>Hardened - Your hardened exterior reduces the Attack Power of incoming attacks, negating the value equal to the attribute rating.<br>Spell Penetration - Bypass enemy Resistances, negating Resistance to the associated damage type by the value of the attribute.<br>Resistant - You are resistant to the specified damage type, reduce Spell Power on spells of this damage type by the value of the attribute.<br>Skills<br>Skills are Innate Abilities that players can use to overcome various challenges in the world. These are determined by Base Attributes, Features and player choices.<br>
<br>Athletics (Strength) - Overcoming feats of physical strength such as a wrestling, lifting heavy objects and jumping.
<br>Acrobatics (Dexterity) - Overcoming feats of agility and quick reaction such as a navigating traps, dodging threats, and acrobatics.
<br>Persuasion (Charisma) - The character's ability to persuade the minds of other, can be used in business negotiations, interrogations and making allies.
<br>Arcana (Intelligence) - Used to gain understanding and overcoming challenges pertaining to magic. This could be magic puzzles, powerful objects, and determining enemy vulnerabilities.
<br>Deception (Charisma) - The character's ability to deceive others, such as lying about their intentions, misdirecting enemies and exaggerating.
<br>Nature (Faith) - The characters knowledge and affinity for nature and animals. Used to interact with animals, identify reagents and determine the vulnerabilities of beasts. 
<br>Intimidation (Charisma, Strength) - Used to convince others to do your bidding through fear. Can be used in interrogations, deterring enemies and haggling.
<br>Religion (Faith) - Used to recall knowledge and overcome challenges pertaining to religion and the occult. This could be solving Faith based puzzles, communing with divine beings or strengthening extraplanar bonds.
<br>Sleight of Hand (Dexterity)  - The characters ability to use their quick hands and dexterous cunning to overcome more illicit challenges. This includes lockpicking, theft, swapping objects and breaking and entering.
<br>Survival (Faith, Intelligence)- The characters knowledge and ability to navigate the wilds and sense danger. This can be used to detect traps, track enemies and look for the signs of an ambush.
<br>Stealth (Dexterity) - The characters ability to conceal themselves in the shadows and avoid enemy detection.
<br>Skills values are calculated by using the associated stat modifier + Skill Expertise:<br>
<br>Novice: +2
<br>Journeyman: +4
<br>Expert: +6
<br>Master: + 8
<br>Legend: +10
]]></description><link>core-gameplay/attributes-&amp;-skills.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Attributes &amp; Skills.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 15:54:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Character Creation]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Players can pick up to two classes from which to build their character from the 9 base classes:<br>
<br>Alchemist - A master of alchemical concoctions, using their potent brews to deal massive damage and increase both defence and combat potency. Alchemists can also specialize in transfiguring materials to create new and exotic mixtures.
<br>Bard - Bard's weave the magic of music into their combat, bewitching the minds of enemies and bolstering their allies. 
<br>Druid - Druid's draw their power from nature and kinship with animals. Druid's can unleash this power to soothe their allies wounds and even take the form of a a bonded animal spirit.
<br>Elementalist - Elementalists channel the powers of the elements to cause devastating damage and restraining their enemies. They can specialize in single elements or weave together multiple elements to build intricate combos. 
<br>Priest - Priests use their divine connections to weave powerful healing magics or unleash pure terror on their enemies.
<br>Ranger - Rangers are versatile and cunning tacticians known for their prowess with ranged weapons. Rangers can use a range of traps and strategies to pick apart even the most stout of defences. 
<br>Rogue - Rogues are masters of the shadows and use lethal hit and run tactics to deal out massive damage. Their guile also extends to their exceptional sleight of hand and silver tongue.
<br>Warlock - Warlocks borrow power from their Demonic Patrons, usually enslaved by powerful binding magics but sometimes more sinister forces are at play. Depending on the Patron, warlocks can channel infernal powers, shadow magic and even summon demonic minions.
<br>After picking their class(es), players can define their characters race and history. See character sheet creator for specifics on each race and their attributes.<br>Attributes:<br>Strength - determines the characters physical strength and raw athletic ability. Directly increases attack power and may be required to equip certain Great Weapons.<br>Dexterity - determines the characters physical agility and reaction time. Can increase attack power with finesse weapons and critical strike chance.<br>Intellect - determines the players capability for wielding the raw forces of magic. Increases spell power and may be required to cast more powerful spells.<br>Faith - determines the strength of the players connection to divine beings. Increases spell power for faith based casters and allows characters to bind themself to more powerful beings.<br>Stamina - determines physical fitness and resilience to enemy attacks. Increases base health points, movement speed and may be required to wear heavier armor types. <br>Charisma - determines the players ability to influence other through deception, performance and persuasion. Also also increases spell power in healing magics and bolstering magics. <br>Starting Deck<br>Players will receive a starting Class Deck with 20 base cards. If multi classing, players can exchange any number of these with cards from their secondary class. <br>Starting Equipment<br>
Based on your class and starting level, you can choose starting equipment to fit your playstyle.<br>
Equipment can increase defence, attack power, spell power and even increase attributes (though not likely for starting equipment)]]></description><link>core-gameplay/character-creation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Character Creation.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 17:21:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Combat]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Updated ideas:<br>
<br>Damage always hits, but the effect may be mitigated
<br>Spell effects will have to overcome the enemies resistance, spells can be stacked to weaken this
<br>Armor negates damage up to its value per round,  armor penetration allows a portion of that armor to be ignored. Flanking attacks will reduce deal double damage to armor. e.g.: If a creature has 15 armor and an attack was rolled for 22 damage -- reduce the attack by 7 instead of 15
<br>Resistances function the same as armor, but for specific damage types. Resistances are not reduced by flanking
<br><br>
<br>Queue - Each player and the DM has a Queue which is where they play their Action, Reaction, Triggered Strategy, and Consumable Cards. Cards will be cleared from the Queue at the end of the combat round unless otherwise specified.
<br>Reserve - Each player and DM has a Reserve where persistent cards are played, such as Buffs / Debuffs, Strategy and Equipment Cards. Reserve Cards stay in play until their effects have expired or are moved to the Field.
<br>Pool - Pool represents the cards that players and the DM have in their hands. The standard Pool size is 5, and you will draw up to this number at the beginning of every combat round.
<br>Discard Pile - Most cards will go to the discard pile after their effect has expired unless otherwise specified. The discard pile will be shuffled when resetting your Deck.
<br>Out of Play - Some cards will have limited uses per Encounter, Rest, or Day. These cards are put Out of Play when their effects have expired. They can be shuffled back into the Deck when their cooldown has finished.
<br>Deck - Players and DM's have a Deck that holds all their available cards. When players reach the end of the deck, they will shuffle the Discard pile to reset it and gain 1 point of Exhaustion. For every two points of exhaustion, your Pool will be reduced by 1.
<br>Field - The field is the combat grid where player and enemy character tokens interact. The field is made up of a grid or hexagon tile pattern where each tile represents 5ft. Movement is always measured as 5ft, even when moving diagonally. When dealing with elevation during combat, to simplify math the distance is calculated as Horizontal Distance + 1/2 Vertical distance. Though it is recommended to avoid using this excessively, try to only emphasize this when vertically is a key part of the encounter.
<br>Action Points - Action Points are the core resource that allow players and enemies to use abilities and make attacks. Most classes have a base of 3 Action Points, these reset at the beginning of the Combat Round unless specified by an effect.
<br>Combat Round - The Combat Round is comprised of 2 phases: Player Turns and Enemy Turns. There is no set turn order between players, and they can plan out their moves strategically if necessary.
<br>Reactions - Players and most enemies will have access to Reactions that have certain triggers. These can be played directly from the player's Pool if available.
<br><br>Combat is what truly separates this from other TTRPG's, as it is centered around a deck building mechanic. Somewhat inspired by games like Slay the Spire, combat has not specific turn order and players can collaborate to enhance each others abilities. There is only two types of combat starts: Player Priority and Enemy Priority, this simply decides whether the players get round first or if the enemy does. This will be determined by the circumstances that lead to combat, and the players choices in how they approach dangerous situations. In combat, players will face three type of enemies: Monsters, Minions, and Bosses.<br>
<br>Monsters:  Any threat can be a monster, not only 'monstrous' creatures, the term is to simply codify the capabilities of an enemy. A Monster is a threatening entity that has a small card pool of abilities that will be added to the DM's hand during combat. They will also have innate abilities and equipment similar to Player Characters.
<br>Minions: Lesser threats that are represented by a single card. Often part of a Monster or Boss's card pool. Their attacks and defence will be stated on the card.
<br>Bosses: Bosses are the big bad enemies that your hero's will aspire to defeat. Offering a much greater challenge and reward than Monsters, a Boss may have a full deck of cards and be accompanied by Monsters and Minions.
<br>At the beginning of the combat, players will draw 5 cards from their deck and if they have priority will play the first combat round. Each player may expend all their action points each turn, and action points are reset on each combat round. Cards will provided a detailed explanation of their effect and damage / defensive value. Some of these effects will be based on the state of combat, the cards available or combinations with other effects.<br>
<br>Resolving Damage: Compare the damage being dealt to the Defence rating of the enemy, the enemy then takes damage equal the amount that exceeds this defence rating. Some enemies may have resistances or immunities to certain damage types.

<br>Resistances are added to the enemies Defence rating when taking damage from the associated type. Most attacks will only inflict a single damage type.
<br>Immunities as the name imply mean that the enemy will not take any damage from this damage type unless an effect otherwise states.


<br>Stronger Monster's and Bosses can react with defensive abilities that may reduce or negate incoming damage. They will usually have a limited number of reactions available per turn. Players will be able to see these values and factor them into their strategy.
<br>Once players have resolved their damage, the enemy will take their turn and repeat the damage resolution process against the players. Each player will have 1 reaction available to use a Defensive Card or Innate Ability. Some equipment may offer additional effects that can be used to bolster Defence further.<br>A cheat sheet for this will be provided later.<br>Running Combat:<br>The goal of combat, like any TTRPG is to continue the narrative and allow opportunities for players to roleplay their characters. As the DM you should encourage your players to describe their actions and keep their dialogue in character. As such, run combat with a goal in mind - perhaps a sub goal that must be achieved to ensure victory or save a friendly NPC. Play the enemies as real living beings with their own goals, intentions, and will to live.<br>Examples:<br>
<br>A random encounter with a set of bandits will not likely fight to the last man and may attempt to flee when they see things are not going their way. They may plead for mercy or attempt to bribe the players. Your goal is to prevent combat from becoming a slog and detracting from the story telling. 
<br>A Boss may have been in fact delaying the players while his master plan unfolds in the background.
<br>Players are fighting in a burning building and must either defeat the enemies or escape before the building collapses. Use timers or limited combat rounds to create time pressure.
<br>Combat Difficulty: <br>Combat Difficulty is often one of the most challenging parts of any TTRPG. Finding the balance between creating a sense of danger and outright lethal encounters can be difficult. It may be worth consulting your players for how difficult they want the game to be, and how dire the consequences of failure are.  <br>Here are some suggestions for managing difficulty:<br>
<br>Adapt to your players abilities - it's often best to start with a lower difficulty and scale it up as your players start to master their class. If they are crushing every combat with ease, this should be an obvious sign that your difficulty is too low -- whereas if they're struggling to survive every single combat then you may want to pull back a bit.
<br>Dynamic Combat Scaling: While enemies may have a set deck and set of abilities, you as the DM can choose how aggressively to play them. If a combat is clearly getting out of hand for the players, you can hold back abilities as you see fit, and even reduce enemies HP if necessary. Your goal should not be TPK's every combat.
<br>Enemies combat potency should be somewhat equivalent to their narrative placement. A random bandit might be a threat early on, but should stand no chance against a geared and levelled party. These distinctions should also be visible to players, allowing them to approach dangerous situations differently depending on the level of threat. In some cases, avoiding combat will be the best option.
<br>Failing forward - Occasionally your party will falter in combat, whether they picked a fight too difficult or simply misplayed their cards. You as the DM should be prepared to offer alternative outcomes to combat that do not result in a party wipe. Bandits may be willing to spare lives for gold, it may be possible to flee from a creature, offering service or fealty to a enemy Boss may allow them to keep their lives (If they so choose). This does not mean removing the possibility of character death, but should be used as a means to continue the narrative.
<br>Player Deaths &amp; Party Wipes:<br> How you deal with player deaths and party wipes is entirely up to you as a DM. Will they be saved at the last moment by deus ex machina, or will their spirits be sent to a shadow realm? Will a players body be put in stasis until the possibility of resurrection? Or will your world be one of more mundane realities, and the dead stay dead. This should be part of your world building, and be planned for in the case of player deaths. Certainly removing the possibility of player death is not advisable, as it takes the danger out of the world -- but you don't want to torpedo your own campaign. Here are some ways you can handle character death:<br>
<br>Offer the player a low penalty reroll, perhaps he can start at the same level but loses his equipment. Or he must complete a redemption quest to prove himself worth of joining the party.
<br>If the player is heavily attached to that character, you can offer them a temporary side role while they attempt to resurrect their character.
<br>On a party wipe, you could have them re-roll as a group of competing adventurers around the same level / equipment. 
<br>Make the players fight their way out of a shadow / death realm and reclaim their physical forms.
<br>Ultimately it's up to you and your players, so don't be afraid to consult them out of game. At the end of the day, they are here to be part of exploring the world and advancing YOUR story. So give them the tools they need to do so while getting maximum enjoyment out of being there. Some players enjoy the ruthless dangers of a lethal world, while others are more interested in the story telling and the ability to roleplay the ever victorious hero.<br>Advanced Combat Concepts:<br>Limited Round Combats:<br>
Giving the players a limited number of combat rounds to resolve an encounter can create a more interesting challenge. This could be imposed by a looming danger or the necessity to achieve a tertiary goal. Be sure to consider what happens when the time runs out, what outcomes are you okay with risking if they fail?<br>Example:<br>
The big bad guy has begun a summoning ritual that will take 10 rounds to complete. If the players do not defeat him in 10 rounds they will find themselves in a much more dire situation.<br>Combat Puzzles<br>A combat puzzle forces the players to attempt to achieve their desired outcome in a combat round by managing and collaborating with their fellow players. Some encounters could be a set of these puzzles, and can be used to great effect when in a particularly lethal situation. <br>Example:<br>
The players are fighting against a cult who's God is empowered by human sacrifice. Each round the players must attempt to stop as many of the cultists as possible from reaching the sacrificial altar that consumes their souls. After 3 rounds, the God will ascend and will have additional health for each cultist consumed. <br>Mitigating Factors<br>
You can give the players the opportunity to reduce the danger of an encounter, this can be done through strategic planning, assassinating leaders or simply poisoning the stew. This rewards players for approaching combat with a more pre meditated mindset.<br>Examples:<br>
Example 1 - The players find out that the corrupt guard Captain is planning to ambush them and arrest them unlawfully. They also find out that his lieutenants are somewhat morally ambivalent towards the idea, and are possibly even opposed to it yet simply outranked. The players can attempt to avoid the ambush altogether, come in better prepared -- or attempt to sway the lieutenants into opposing the Captain in secret. This could create a scenario when they intentionally walk into the ambush and are able to turn it around and expose the treachery of the Captain.  <br>Example 2 - The players are planning to attack a vampire lord, and it is revealed that this lord draws his power from the souls of other vampires he's managed to enslave. These souls are being guarded at different locations throughout the world and could be destroyed to reduce the vampire lords power.]]></description><link>core-gameplay/combat.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Combat.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 12:36:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Damage Types]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>There are several major damage categories in the world, each with a subset of damage types.<br>Physical Damage<br>Physical damage is one of the most common damage types you'll find in the world. This includes:<br>
<br>Slashing - Caused by bladed weapons, claws and other sharp sweeping attacks
<br>Piercing - Caused by puncturing weapons, teeth and most high speed projectiles
<br>Bludgeoning - Blunt force damage caused by heavy blunt weapons, fists, and collisions with large objects
<br>Physical damage is mitigated by Equipping Armour and Shields and a large amount of Defensive abilities.<br>Elemental Damage<br>Elemental damage is dealt by those wielding the forces of nature, environmental factors and infused weapons. There are 4 sources of Elemental Damage:<br>
<br>Fire - Dealt by Fire spells, Fire and Fire Infused Weapons
<br>Cold - Dealt by Cold spells, long exposure to the cold, and Cold Infused Weapons
<br>Arcane - Dealt by Arcane spells, raw magic sources and Arcane Infused Weapons
<br>Lightning - Dealt by Lightning spells, Lightning, and Lightning Infused Weapons
<br>Elemental damage can be mitigated by Resistances and Immunities as well as certain Defensive abilities.<br>Occult Damage<br>Occult damage is dealt by those wielding the power of Extraplanar and Divine Beings. It's unique in that it has it's own distinct sub-categories:<br>Good:<br>
Good damage types typically come from Good or Neutral aligned Divine Beings and is wielded by their followers. There are 2 Good damage types:<br>
<br>Light - Light damage is dealt by Light spells and Blessed Weapons. Some Evil creatures can also be damaged by Sun Light.
<br>Radiant - Radiant damage is a combination of Light and Fire damage types and can be dealt by Radiant Spells and Holy Weapons. <a data-footref="1" href="about:blank#fn-1-efaedc722f0c5d45" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[1]</a>
<br>Neutral:<br>
Neutral Damage Types come from Neutral aligned Divine Beings and is wielded by their followers, as well as the the Practitioners of Natures magic<br>
<br>Nature - Nature damage is a distillation of the forces of Nature and is dealt by Nature spells and most poisons.
<br>Force - Force damage is the manifestation of pure raw energy and cannot be mitigated by Resistances or Immunities. Force damage is dealt by Force spells and some Divine Weapons<a data-footref="2" href="about:blank#fn-2-efaedc722f0c5d45" class="footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">[2]</a>.
<br>Evil:<br>
Evil Damage Types come from Evil and some Neutral aligned Divine Beings and is wielded by their followers and some sorcerers who study the occult.<br>
<br>Shadow - Shadow damage is a manifestation of the dark forces of the world. Dealt by Shadow Spells and Desecrated Weapons
<br>Chaos - Chaotic Energies most often found in the Abyss. Dealt by Chaos spells and Demonforged Weapons
<br>Infernal - Infernal is a compound of Chaos and Fire, dealt by Infernal magic and Infernal Weapons
<br><br><br>
<br>
<br>Compound damage types, while having the advantage of being multiple damage types also can be repelled by a Resistance or Immunity of their parent category.<a href="about:blank#fnref-1-efaedc722f0c5d45" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow"></a>
<br>Divine Weapons are exceptionally rare unique weapons that were created by Divine Beings. These Weapons often alter the world around them and deal raw Force damage.<a href="about:blank#fnref-2-efaedc722f0c5d45" class="footnote-backref footnote-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow"></a>
]]></description><link>core-gameplay/damage-types.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Damage Types.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 01:17:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Decks and Cards]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Decks are the core of the gameplay experience, and are a collection of cards offering a variety of combat effects. There are 4 main types of cards: Actions, Items, Consumables, and Strategy.<br>
<br>Action - Action cards represent actions that the players characters can take during combat. These include attacks, defensive reactions, spells and buffs. Action spells will have a action point cost and are discarded after use unless otherwise specified by an effect. 

<br>Each class receives a set of 'Basic' Action cards for simple melee attacks and defensive actions.
<br>Additional cards are selected on level up, or can be received as rewards for encounters, purchased from trainers and even found in the world.


<br>Items - Item cards are usable items that can be purchased or found and added to a players deck. Item cards may have certain class requirements to play. Items stay on the playing field until destroyed or consumed by their effect. Some items can be repaired if destroyed, this will be specified on the card.
<br>Consumables - Consumables or limited use cards that are held separately from your main hand. This includes things such as potions, scrolls and throwables. 
<br>Strategies - Strategy cards are class specific cards that have context specific effects. They are played face down and activated only when the conditions are met. Players can show these to their team mates but keep the effect hidden from the DM. Some strategy cards may require all the players to work towards a shared goal.
<br><br>When players create their character they will receive a base starting deck from their selected class that has 20 cards. If they are multi-classing, they can exchange any number of starting cards with cards from their secondary class's starting deck.<br>Each time the player levels up they can add 2 cards from their Class Level Up Deck. These can be split between multiple classes if multi-classing.<br>Powerful enemies, vendors and sometimes unique locations can offer powerful and unique cards.<br>Players may have cards that are not currently usable or in use, these can be added to their Collection. After a long rest, players can exchange cards from their Collection with those in their Deck while preparing for the day.<br><br>While there are no level requirements on cards, some cards will have requirements to be used or played. Some are tied to class, attribute values or weapon specializations. Players can keep cards for later use in their Collection.<br><br>All classes have a base capacity of 3 consumables with the exception of Alchemist that starts with 5. This repertoire can be expanded with certain items and class features. Consumables can be stored in the players collection, and swapped during daily preparations. While they are not part of the Players Deck, they still may require action points. <br><br>Strategy cards are rare and powerful cards that allow the party to set up for powerful effects by completing the listed conditions. Strategy cards effects can be hidden from DM and revealed when the conditions are met.<br>Examples: <br>Harmonious Assault:<br>
Condition - Every player in the party  must deal damage with an attack action in a single combat round.<br>
Each party member gains 3 additional Action Points on the next round. This card is discarded after the effect is triggered.<br>Master of the Elements:<br>
Condition - Deal damage with 3 different elemental damage types during a combat encounter.<br>
Effect(s) - Perform an Elemental Blast, dealing 5 damage of each element used to trigger the blast.<br><br>Players can expand their Decks through levelling up, defeating powerful enemies, buying from vendors and treasure hunting. There are two categories of Cards: Class Cards, and Primal Cards.<br>Class Cards - Class Cards are gained from levelling up and class specific feats. Class cards are specific to your class or sub class. Players can pick 2 Class Cards on each level up from either of their classes if multi-classing. Players can also find Masters of those classes throughout the world that will allow them to rebuild their class Deck for a price.<br>Primal Cards - Primal Cards are non class specific cards that are tied to specific Martial, Arcane and Occult abilities.  There are 7 Primal Card Types.<br><br>Cards that represent abilities and spells that harness the raw power of the elements. Most often wielded by Elementalists and Druids, these spells have massive damage potential and can control the battlefield. There are 4 subtypes of Elemental Cards:<br>
<br>Arcane - Spells and abilities that channel to raw elemental forces of magic. These spells have some of the most potent effects available, but are very costly to cast.
<br>Fire - Fire Cards channel the destructive power of Fire to deal massive Area of Effect Damage. Fire can be a fickle ally and needs to be wielded with care or the caster may end up burning themselves or their allies.
<br>Cold - Cold Cards suck the very energy from the air around them, draining their unfortunate targets of their power. Cold spells are the perfect tool to control the battlefield and ensuring the enemies are incapable of retaliating. 
<br>Storm- These spells are used to decimate large numbers of enemies and cause dehabilitating paralysis. Dealing large amounts of Lightning damage and using strong winds to tear apart enemy defences.
<br><br>Evil cards use abilities believed to draw their power from Evil beings and sources. While this is not exclusively true, casting Evil spells will often draw negative attention from Neutral and Good aligned beings. It is also often considered an anathema for followers of Good aligned Gods. There are 3 subtypes of Evil Cards:<br>
<br>Chaos - Chaos spells call on the chaotic energies of the Abyss, terrorizing their enemies and enslaving demonic forces to do your bidding. 
<br>Infernal - Infernal spells channel the powers of the Hells, harnessing the potent destructive capability of Hellfire and binding their enemies with pact magic.
<br>Shadow - Shadow spells call upon the dark energies of the universe, using the power of Death and Decay to drain and wear down their victims. Shadow energies also permeate and claw at the enemies minds.
<br><br>Good cards use abilities believed to draw their power from Good beings and sources. As with Evil cards, this is not always the case -- but these spells will usually be perceived positively by all except the Evil aligned.  Good spells may be anathemic to Evil Gods. There are 2 types of Good Cards:<br>
<br>Light - Light spells channel the powers of Divine Light to soothe their allies wounds and repel the forces of Evil. Light spells are often used to empower allies and create impenetrable defences.
<br>Radiant - Radiant spell combine the powers of Light with the fury of Fire, calling on the Divine Fury of the Gods. Radiant spells can be used to deal massive damage to the forces of Evil, and and protect those who wield them and their allies. 
<br><br>Neutral cards represent powers and abilities drawn from Neutral aligned gods and the balanced energies of Nature. Neutral abilities can also come from both Good and Evil Gods depending on their domains. It is not common for Neutral cards to be anathema, but some Gods may see Neutral as the absence of Good or Evil and therefore condemn these abilities. There are 2 Neutral subtypes:<br>
<br>Force - Force represents the raw energies of the universe and cannot be mitigated by Resistances or Immunities. Force spells are notoriously difficult to manage and therefore tend to have lower damage values than other damage types. Though can become invaluable when overcoming enemies with high Resistances, making them incredibly reliable as a damage source. They also are often used to manipulate the world around them and create illusions.
<br>Nature - Nature cards call on the powers of Nature and are incredibly versatile. From potent damage spells to reviving allies and ensnaring enemies -- Nature abilities give those who wield them to tools to deal with almost any situation.
<br><br>Martial cards represent the skills and abilities that Men and other beings have cultivated over millenias of war. Martial cards are used by those who prefer to go toe to toe with their enemies, mastering the instruments of war and even fighting hand to hand. There are 4 Martial subtypes:<br>
<br>Way of the Fist - Way of the Fist cards are used by those looking to master hand to hand combat, using strikes and grapples to control and teardown enemies. 
<br>Berserker - Berserker cards are used by those who are able to tap into their inner rage and fearlessly leap into any battle. Berserker cards have huge damage potential and allow the wielder to channel the pain of their wounds into deadly counter attacks.
<br>Tactician - Tacticians are masters of war, with a balanced approach to offence and defence. They use Strategies to share their battle prowess with their allies and inspire those around them.
<br>Knight - Knights are expertly trained in the instruments of war, wielding a large variety of Weapons and Armour types. Knight cards can be used to decimate the battlefield while offering a wide array of Defensive options. 
<br>Fighter - Fighters are master skirmishers, wielding Finesse weapons with unmatched skill to shred their enemies. Fighters are highly mobile and can weave in and out of battle, relying on their guile to avoid enemy attacks.
<br>Marksman - Marksman cards are used by those who look to specialize in ranged weaponry. Their pinpoint aim and agile reflexes make them incredibly potent combatants. Marksman also wield a variety of tools to bolster their survival and slow down enemies.
<br><br>Subterfuge cards represent the lethal abilities of those who strike from the shadows. Users of these cards prefer to wait for opportune moments to attack and find weak points in their enemies armour. The cards have massive damage potential but require a degree of finesse to execute to maximum effect. There are 4 Subterfuge subtypes:<br>
<br>Assassin - Assassins will wait for the perfect opening to deal incredible single target damage. They use their training and guile to turn around combat encounters and strike terror into their enemies. Assassin cards will often have huge Critical Strike potential, but may require certain conditions to be met.
<br>Trickster - Tricksters use sleight of hand and illusions to confuse their enemies, capitalizing on moments of weakness with lightning quick strikes.
<br>Swashbuckler  - Swashbucklers keep their enemies on their toes with confusing battle antics and relying on luck and guile to take down enemies with style. Swashbuckler cards often use Chance dice to determine outcomes and humiliate their enemies.
<br>Operator - Operator cards are used by those who employ their mastery of Traps, Equipment and Consumables to outwit and obliterate their enemies. Operator cards have an emphasis on equipment and combat mobility, and Operator specialists can also expand their Consumable Capacity.
<br><br>Melody cards are a unique category of abilities and spells used by those who weave powerful magics through song and melody. Famed for their ability to empower allies, they can also cause confusion among enemies and increase Defence. There are 3 Melody subtypes:<br>
<br>Classical - Classical melodies create order from the primal energies of the universe, bolstering allies Defence, empowering their attacks and even taking away their weariness.
<br>Modern - Modern cards create unpredictable melodies that can cause confusion among enemies and deal area of effect damage. They are also used to increase ally's Spell Power.
<br>Experimental - Experimental melodies attempt to create melodies with the chaotic energies of the universe.  They can cause massive damage and inspire allies with increased mobility and attack power.
]]></description><link>core-gameplay/decks-and-cards.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Decks and Cards.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 17:55:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dice]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Dice are used to determine damage, probability and other random events in the world.<br>Damage Dice - Damage dice are rolled to determine the damage that an attack deals. These include D4, D6, D8, D10 and D12.<br>Defensive Dice - Defensive dice are rolled when attempting to mitigate damage. Subtract the Defence roll from the damage being dealt. Defensive Dice are the same as the Damage Dice.<br>Chance Dice - Used to determine Chance outcomes, such as Critical Strikes and Luck. The DM's can also use this to determine random outcomes. This is a D20.<br>Skill Dice - Rolled when determining Skill outcomes such as Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, Athletics, Acrobatics and Knowledge. D20 is the standard dice used for these rolls.]]></description><link>core-gameplay/dice.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Dice.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 12:49:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Equipment]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Equipment can play an essential part of Player's and some Bosses power, defence, and even utility. There is a wide array of mundane and magically equipment in the world that can be found, taken or purchased to increase your combat potency.<br><br>Armour increases your characters survivability in battle, potentially increasing the amount mitigated per Defence Rating. Each type of mundane armour has an associated Damage Die.<br><br>Light Armour: D6<br>
Medium Armour: D8<br>
Heavy Armour: D10<br>Magic Armour can be more varied and may provide additional benefits.<br><br>Dwarf Forged Mithril Vest: D12 Defence Die and has the trait Impenetrable: This armour is immune to Armour Penetration effects.<br>Shimmering Astral Robe: D4 Defence Die and has the trait Astral Shimmer: Once per combat round you can use the Free Action Astral Shift: You take half damage from the next attack this combat round.<br>Hauberk of Vengeance D8 Defence die and has the trait Aura of Vengeance: Each combat round that you take damage gain a stack of Rising Vengeance that last until the end of the encounter. You gain the ability Burst of Vengeance(2): Consume all stacks of Rising Vengeance, you let out a burst of Radiant energy, damaging all enemies in a 30ft radius, dealing 1 Damage die per stack.<br>Your proficiency in each armour type determines how effectively you use it:<br>
Untrained: 1 DR<br>
Proficient: 2 DR<br>
Expert: 3 DR<br>
Master: 4 DR]]></description><link>core-gameplay/equipment.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Equipment.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 16:16:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Exploring the World]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Exploration will play in a very similar fashion to other TTRPG's. The DM will guide the players and weave the narrative as they see fit. Players can use their classes 'Innate Abilities' to interact with and influence the world around them in the same way you might see in Dungeon's &amp; Dragons. That being said, the DM does have a few tools in their chest that can utilize the RNG and Card mechanics of the game. The Random Events deck allows the DM to add an element of randomness, flesh out a traversal sequence, or simply create an element of unpredictability in a dungeon. This deck can be tailored to the zone or simply be a collection of scripted events and encounters.<br>Non Combat Encounters - Players have access to Innate Abilities that allow them to navigate out of combat situations using Dice rolls to determine outcomes. Social interactions can be roleplayed like any other TTRPG and puzzles can be overcome using magic and feats of strength. Using your Combat Deck's cards in social situations will often be received with hostility, if not direct retaliation.]]></description><link>core-gameplay/exploring-the-world.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Exploring the World.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 19:20:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Summary]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>To build a simple but more engaging combat system for tabletop RPG's using cards to represent action economy. To maintain a semblance of RPG progression on top of deck building mechanics as well as traditional positional elements of combat.<br><br>Much of the core gameplay will feel familiar to TTRPG players, especially of common games like D&amp;D and Pathfinder. The main differences will be in the combat system, where traditional TTRPG combat will be supplemented by cards that represent a players action economy. <br><br>Myself and many people I have played with find the save or suck and repetitive nature of TTRPG combat can bog down games and take away the enjoyment from the greater scope of the game. Cards allow for more interesting spell interactions that may break balance in traditional combat, as well as the slot machine effect of drawing the perfect situational card. They also provide a constant route for player progression that is not tied purely to stat or gear upgrades.<br><br>The first step is to extract what I feel to be essential parts of traditional TTRPG's and maintain the core roleplaying and progression. Then to reimagine the classes so that each deck has a clear identity, but leaves room for player experimentation like a proper deck builder. I believe that part of the key to achieving this is to maintain some of the standard character progression from TTRPGs, such as stat scaling and gearing. This means keeping very tight damage numbers and scalable math that won't become an overhead for players and DM's.]]></description><link>core-gameplay/summary.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Core Gameplay/Summary.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 12:09:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Religions & Gods]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Gods and Divine Beings are real and quite preset in the world, constantly warring and playing]]></description><link>lore/religions-&amp;-gods.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Lore/Religions &amp; Gods.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 01:22:01 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>